[dramatic sound]
Lara.
Lara?
Hey, Lara!
Lara.
Lara!
Lara...
what is it that you really want?
[thud]
[ROWAN] Beautiful.
This is how...
you were supposed to be.
[gasps] Father!
Are you okay?
Father!
[creaking]
[ROWAN] I used the power
of our royal spear
to dispel the evil
curse of that potion.
Having the legs of those
hideous humans
will twist the light and
cloud your eyes,
making you forget who you are.
-What are you-—
-Now is the time.
Fulfill your destiny
as a princess.
You have to use your blade.
Use it to pierce your
loved one with it.
You must purify the light,
and then those hideous
- humans will fight-—
- But why?
You don't need to know why.
[rumbling]
[gasps]
No, it's falling apart!
- Lara, you have to save Father!
- [gasps]
Where am I?
[helicopter whirring]
[magical sound]
Ever since a new species
of aquatic plant
was spotted in Lake Biwa,
Shiga Prefecture, this month,
there have been reports
of unidentified microorganisms
and ecosystem disruptions.
[phone vibrating]
[YOSHIYA] Dad, can you hear me?
It's Mari.
Mari's in trouble.
It's the boat. We're looking,
but we can't find her anywhere.
-Mari.
- Calling around-—
Kota!
The place-— it's crumbling.
The witch's power
is beginning to fade,
but Father is also losing
his strength by the minute.
We're running out of time.
[sighs]
[underwater sounds]
No,
I can't go back anywhere.
Not even to the surface.
Nowhere.
Why would you say that?
Why, Father?
It isn't fair.
Humans aren't hideous at all.
The time I spent
with them all gave me
is something irreplaceable.
So I could never do it.
Stab someone I love?
There's no way.
No way.
[LUNA] Lara?
[gasps]
I think I can hear...
Lara's voice.
-Luna!
-I can hear it.
The voice...
of the Princess of Light.
Yes, that's it.
The voice of our beloved sister.
Lara, give us light.
You can do it.
I know you can.
Do it for us.
So then, this time,
pierce right through them.
Pierce straight through the
souls of humans.
Through the hearts of those
hideous human beings.
-I hate them.
-I hate every single human.
They stole the light
from all of us.
They took your love for
granted and betrayed you.
I hate humans so much.
And so do you, deep down.
Even now, because that hatred
won't fade away.
And because you've
been crying all this time.
[underwater sounds]
[♪ opening music begins]
EDITING AND TYPESETTING:
ASHLEY BARBOZA
[♪ opening music ends]
[Lisa sobs]
[footsteps]
It's you.
Just what are you doing here?
-[MARI] Is he okay?
-Stop.
Why are you here?
I have to see Lara.
I want to help her.
So she called you then?
[MARI] She told me
not to come here,
but...
[helicopter whirring]
Lara is over there,
in the place shrouded in fog.
If you want to see her,
just walk that way.
Go on.
Thank you.
You'll die.
If you go to that
place... you will die.
You can't see that blade,
can you? There in the sky.
-[MARI] A blade?
-[LISA] That's right.
It's Lara's actual heart
floating in midair.
You can't see it.
After all, you're only human.
The true light...
is invisible to humans.
Mermaids and humans, we both
came from the same sea once.
However, you humans chose
to close your eyes
until... you couldn't
see anything at all.
You're just a mere human!
You don't know!
You can't possibly understand
Lara or any of us!
Us mermaids, we're
noble beings of light!
But you!
You turned your backs on
the light and on true love!
There's no way you can begin
to understand her!
[MARI] I can't see
into Lara's heart,
and so I have to get closer.
That is why I have to go
and be with her.
[KOTA] I don't want Lady
Lara to have to kill...
someone who she loves dearly.
[Lisa sobs]
Because I also... have
someone... I love too.
[Lisa cries]
I hate...
those humans.
[bubbling]
[phone buzzes]
Ah! Mari?
Hey, Mari, is that you?
-Can you hear me, big bro?
-Yeah, but I don't understand.
- Where are you right now?
-Fukushima.
Huh? Why are you there?
I'm sorry, signal is
really weak here.
You idiot! Don't you know
it's total chaos here?
I'm sorry, but it'll be okay.
-I'll be back once I get Lara.
-Uh, wait, Lara's there too?
Lara! Hey, Mari, is Lara there?
-Yeah, she's here.
-Oh! Okay, great.
-I'm heading there now.
-You can't.
What are you talking about?
Look...
I hurt Lara and I feel
responsible for that.
Please, I just want to help
out in any way I can.
All right, why don't you
tell her about yourself
later today when
they bring her home?
-[gasps]
- Thank you, Mari.
- [MARI] Lara?
- Uh? Mari.
-Lara!
-[LARA] You shouldn't be here!
Stay away,
otherwise...
- I might kill you.
- [gasps]
Lara...
[LARA] I guess in the end
I never found true love.
I suppose after all,
I'm a mermaid...
and you're all human.
I tried to ignore that truth...
but it grew within me
during my 200-year sleep.
It was a hatred so intense,
I'm frightened to
even think about it.
I can't erase this turmoil
in my heart. It won't go.
So as long as this hatred
remains within us,
the only fate awaiting
mermaids and humans
is to devour one another.
So then, this princess
must vanish...
so that no one else gets hurt.
I will put an end to this fate.
Have you forgotten
the promise we made?
We promised each other
I would become a pro boxer
and you would make
me a delicious giant cake.
That's enough. You
and I are totally different.
We see different things.
We live in different worlds.
Stay away!
Please, please,
don't come any closer!
It's useless, you and I,
a mermaid and a human.
We're completely
different beings.
[♪ dramatic music]
[MARI] Yeah, we are
completely different.
I mean, you're an idiot,
you're annoying,
you're always getting in my way.
But that's why...
when I'm with you,
I no longer feel alone.
[♪ dramatic music]
I don't care about fate.
Lara... weren't you-—
weren't we both...
born to love somebody,
no matter who or why?
[piercing sound]
[helicopter whirring]
Mari?
Mari!
[helicopter whirring]
[LARA] Mari!
Mari!
No, wake up!
Please, Mari!
No!
[high-pitched chime]
The light.
The light of the one...
I love.
I have...
always wanted it.
The light.
[RIGMOR] What was it
that you really wanted?
[GRACE] What did
you really need,
Lara?
[grunts]
No! Shut up!
I don't need anything!
It would've been fine
if I just disappeared!
Don't care at all
what happens to me,
but you have to stay
here in this world!
[intense rumbling]
Mari...
[underwater rumbling]
[gasps]
[piercing sound]
[Lara screams]
It hurts!
[slash]
[LARA] I can't move.
[LARA] I'm not able to save you.
[slash]
[LARA] Is this it?
Is this what happens?
The fate that awaits
mermaids and humans?
I really wish...
I hadn't come back to life.
Lara?
No.
No!
I'm glad I came back to life!
I'm glad I got to come
back to the surface!
Even now, I'm still glad of
everything! I've no regrets!
That's just who I am.
I am-—
I'm clumsy, a nuisance,
a total idiot of a mermaid.
But so what if I'm an idiot?
So what if that's who I am?
Don't underestimate me!
It's a lie that I'd rather
just disappear.
Even...
if I had to stay in this form,
I'd still want to
stay in this world.
Because of this world...
you're here.
[energy humming]
I,
I...
I'm supposed to find real
love, but I don't want it.
[chimes]
[flaking]
All I want,
[♪ soft music]
[magical sound]
All I want...
is to be alive in a world
where-— you're here.
[♪ soft music continues]
[chimes]
[gasps]
[♪ soft music continues]
[chimes]
[YOSHI] Oh man,
my dad's gonna kill me.
I just know it.
What are you looking at?
[LUCA] The sky...
it just flashed.
Uh?
[water splashes]
[MARI] So did I just
die or something?
-[LARA] Yes.
-[MARI] Hmm...
[LARA] What do you mean "hmm"?
Well, I came back
to life after dying.
I guess that really does
make me the strongest.
I guess.
-Mari.
-Hmm?
So I think the entire time...
I was searching for something.
I was searching for
a world to live in
all along.
[magical sound]
It's been 6 months
since the phenomenon occurred
in Lake Biwa.
Water quality data has
returned to normal levels,
and the excessive
proliferation of phytoplankton
has now largely subsided.
Although Lake Biwa is
gradually returning to normal,
experts are unsure as
to what exactly happened.
[LISA] I wonder, did you
actually find true love?
The light that you found...
it's so different
from anything
we've known until now.
However, Father and
all of the others,
they've begun to regain
their power once again.
They'll all fully
wake up someday,
whether it's in a year
or even 10 years from now.
But when they do,
their hatred towards humans
won't fade. It never will.
[LARA] Even so, I'll reach out
and talk to Father
and the others over and over,
as long as it takes.
I'll talk about the future of
mermaids and humans
because I'm sure that's the
specific light I have found.
[♪ soft piano music]
[sighs]
I couldn't admit it
for a long time
that I was actually
afraid of you.
I was afraid of the way
you were changing.
But... now...
I want you to hold on to this
for now and in the future.
Thank you.
[♪ soft piano music continues]
[LUCA] You know, you're
always so impulsive, Lara.
- [LARA] Impulsive?
- You show up out of the blue,
and then just as
quick you disappear.
I guess that's true.
Like, you had that urge
to want to date me,
and suddenly
wanting to break up.
-It kind of hurt.
-I'm sorry.
Try to see it from
my perspective.
I'm really sorry.
Now, the world's open,
where will you go?
Let's see,
I guess I'll head to where
a new light is waiting.
Lara! I forgot to say,
I finished your portrait.
Come see it sometime.
So you didn't repaint it?
Idiot! You'd actually be shocked
if you saw it.
It's a masterpiece.
[YOSHI] Man, I'm so lonely.
Just how long are
you going to sulk for?
[YOSHI] I'm not sulking.
Lara, walk you to the station?
Oh, thank you, but I'm going
shopping with Mari first.
- Huh?
- Don't forget you've
- got a shift later on.
- Take care.
All right, now don't be
a stranger.
That's right. Come back
anytime, Lara. Okay?
-I'm already hungry again.
-Didn't you eat enough food?
I've been adding more to my
workout routine lately.
Oh?
I've got a tough
session later today.
Just don't overdo it, okay?
I should tell you that.
Do you think you can
live on your own?
Of course I can.
-[MARI] Are you sure?
-[LARA] I'm sure.
The train now arrivi-—
You'll probably
mess something up.
Probably.
Platform one-—
You won't be back
for a while, huh?
Mm-mm.
Please step behind
the yellow line.
[MARI] So then
all that embarrassing
stuff you were saying
about wanting to go
with me or whatever.
-[LARA] Yes, it's true.
-So then why are you leaving?
I'll be...
so lonely.
[Mari cries]
Mari.
[train braking]
The train just arrived at
platform 1. It's the 10:50
service bound for
Kobe via Kakogawa.
- [gasps]
-I'm okay.
Are your legs still hurting you?
Mm-hmm.
- But...
- [sighs]
these wounds are who I am,
and so I'll keep walking
on these feet from this day on.
[door closing]
[panting]
[continues panting]